<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on csgeek Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.esamir.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on csgeek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 10:04:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.esamir.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GCP Google IPv6 Kubernetes support</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/4/29/gcp-google-ipv6-kubernetes-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 10:04:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/4/29/gcp-google-ipv6-kubernetes-support/</guid>
      <description>Assumptions Implementation  IPV6 Config Load Balancer Backend Configuration LoadBalancer FrontEnd configuration Verification   Closing Notes  HTTPS    Most technical writes and writers in general tend to write in content in the hope that there will be value in their contribution for a good while. Usually most of the content I write is mainly for my own purposes to preserve the directions because I struggled to find a solution online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Backup Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/7/home-backup-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/7/home-backup-solution/</guid>
      <description>Home Backup Solution  Choosing Storage Solution Backup Service  Systemd Service     BackUp Data  Encryption Destination Source Schedule Backup Retention   Final Step, Backup Duplicati References/ Requirements  Home Backup Solution I setup a NAS a while ago using Arch Linux and ZFS migrating away from Synology. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice to control your data and be able to use more advanced tooling then the limited set of applications that are available from Synology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toxicity Of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/12/23/the-toxicity-of-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:39:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/12/23/the-toxicity-of-open-source/</guid>
      <description>My most recent experiences though really saddened me and exposed a certain toxicity in the OSS community that I really wish wasn&amp;rsquo;t so prevalent.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting on and off on dev.to but I never introduced myself so let me preface this post with a bit about me to give some context.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using open source and Linux on and off since the early 2000s. My first Linux distribution was Caldera 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker IPV6 Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/docker-ipv6-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/docker-ipv6-guide/</guid>
      <description>IPV4 IPV6  Step 1, enable in the Daemon Step 2, Firewall rules Step 3, Docker Compose + IPV6 Step 4, Resolve NAT Issues   Final thoughts. Unconfirmed Fix  I spent a good bit of time trying to figure this out, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d record this for posterity&amp;rsquo;s sake and others might benefit.
Assumptions:
 You are somewhat familiar with docker You have some exposure with docker-compose You have at least a basic understanding of networking fundamentals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Raid 1 to Raid 5 on Linux file systems</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/22/converting-raid-1-to-raid-5-on-linux-file-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/22/converting-raid-1-to-raid-5-on-linux-file-systems/</guid>
      <description>Converting from Raid 1 to Raid 5 This assumes you have a functional Raid 1 and wish to convert it to a Raid 5.
Disclaimer: At some point during this process I realized that I had a bad mother board. The reason my /dev/sdd1 failed wasn&amp;rsquo;t the drive, but the bus on the board. That being said, this is the unverified procedure.
I&amp;rsquo;m running on Ubuntu 12.10 but you should be able to do this on any modern Linux distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>