<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on csgeek Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.esamir.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on csgeek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.esamir.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Kubernetes Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/15/awesome-kubernetes-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/15/awesome-kubernetes-resources/</guid>
      <description>A much more comprehensive list can be found here. This is likely a subset of the items in that repo and a few additions of tools i&amp;rsquo;ve tried out or want to try out to make my K8s life easier.
CLI Tools:
 Helm Kubernetes package manager K9s CLI management tool. kube-shell integrated shell environment  Cluster Provisioning
 kind Docker based kubernetes deployment. minikube VM based cross-platform kubernetes with addons support  Automation and CI/CD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Backup Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/7/home-backup-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/7/home-backup-solution/</guid>
      <description>Home Backup Solution I setup a NAS a while ago using Arch Linux and ZFS migrating away from Synology. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice to control your data and be able to use more advanced tooling then the limited set of applications that are available from Synology.
I had S3 backups setup with Synology and wanted to create something similar on the Arch Server.
I have about 3 TB of data I want to backup and was looking for something that&amp;rsquo;s secure and is a bit more intelligent than a crontab of aws sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toxicity Of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/12/23/the-toxicity-of-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:39:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/12/23/the-toxicity-of-open-source/</guid>
      <description>My most recent experiences though really saddened me and exposed a certain toxicity in the OSS community that I really wish wasn&amp;rsquo;t so prevalent.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting on and off on dev.to but I never introduced myself so let me preface this post with a bit about me to give some context.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using open source and Linux on and off since the early 2000s. My first Linux distro was Caldera 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker IPV6 Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/docker-ipv6-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/docker-ipv6-guide/</guid>
      <description>I spent a good bit of time trying to figure this out, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d record this for posterity&amp;rsquo;s sake and others might benefit.
Assumptions:
 You are somewhat familiar with docker You have some exposure with docker-compose You have at least a basic understanding of networking fundamentals. I&amp;rsquo;m not a networking expert but you should have an understanding of TCP, the existence of IPV4 and IPV6 and how they differ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Docker Deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/poor-mans-docker-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/poor-mans-docker-deployment/</guid>
      <description>I have had several use cases where I want to deploy things in docker for multiple reasons, but ease of deployment is a big one. Low entry bar, less maintenance that makes docker deployment more appealing. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the resources to do a full K8 deployment and ended up with this pattern I wanted to share with others
Assumptions:
 You are somewhat familiar with docker You have some exposure with docker-compose You know what systemd, init.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Raid 1 to Raid 5 on Linux file systems</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/22/converting-raid-1-to-raid-5-on-linux-file-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/22/converting-raid-1-to-raid-5-on-linux-file-systems/</guid>
      <description>Converting from Raid 1 to Raid 5 This assumes you have a functional Raid 1 and wish to convert it to a Raid 5.
Disclaimer: At some point during this process I realized that I had a bad mother board. The reason my /dev/sdd1 failed wasn&amp;rsquo;t the drive, but the bus on the board. That being said, this is the unverified procedure.
I&amp;rsquo;m running on Ubuntu 12.10 but you should be able to do this on any modern Linux distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>