<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on csgeek Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.esamir.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on csgeek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 10:04:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.esamir.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GCP Google IPv6 Kubernetes support</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/4/29/gcp-google-ipv6-kubernetes-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 10:04:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/4/29/gcp-google-ipv6-kubernetes-support/</guid>
      <description>Assumptions Implementation  IPV6 Config Load Balancer Backend Configuration LoadBalancer FrontEnd configuration Verification   Closing Notes  HTTPS    Most technical writes and writers in general tend to write in content in the hope that there will be value in their contribution for a good while. Usually most of the content I write is mainly for my own purposes to preserve the directions because I struggled to find a solution online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Email Development Service</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/4/21/local-email-development-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/4/21/local-email-development-service/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on any application that sends out emails it&amp;rsquo;s always an issue on how to mimic the behavior on my local laptop. Usually wherever the app is deployed is configured to be able to just &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo;. aka you can send email by connecting to localhost with no auth.
Now, how do I mimic locally? In the past i&amp;rsquo;ve tried setting up postfix etc in a docker stack, or more recently doing an smtp relay using google services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LetsEncrypt SSL DNS automation with lego</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/17/letsencrypt-ssl-dns-automation-with-lego/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 15:47:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/17/letsencrypt-ssl-dns-automation-with-lego/</guid>
      <description>Lego and LetsEncrypt  Dependencies/Tooling SSL Ghost Web Site  Systemd startup script Final Notes on ghost   Nginx SSL Wrapping  Backup Strategies   Final Notes    Lego and LetsEncrypt if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about letsencrypt you should. If you&amp;rsquo;re still serving all your traffic over HTTP you should stop and move over the HTTPS everything. Honestly at this point there shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be any reason not to use SSL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Kubernetes Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/15/awesome-kubernetes-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/15/awesome-kubernetes-resources/</guid>
      <description>A much more comprehensive list can be found here. This is likely a subset of the items in that repo and a few additions of tools i&amp;rsquo;ve tried out or want to try out to make my K8s life easier.
CLI Tools:
 Helm Kubernetes package manager K9s CLI management tool. kube-shell integrated shell environment  Cluster Provisioning
 kind Docker based kubernetes deployment. minikube VM based cross-platform kubernetes with addons support  Automation and CI/CD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Backup Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/7/home-backup-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/21/3/7/home-backup-solution/</guid>
      <description>Home Backup Solution  Choosing Storage Solution Backup Service  Systemd Service     BackUp Data  Encryption Destination Source Schedule Backup Retention   Final Step, Backup Duplicati References/ Requirements  Home Backup Solution I setup a NAS a while ago using Arch Linux and ZFS migrating away from Synology. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice to control your data and be able to use more advanced tooling then the limited set of applications that are available from Synology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toxicity Of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/12/23/the-toxicity-of-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:39:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/12/23/the-toxicity-of-open-source/</guid>
      <description>My most recent experiences though really saddened me and exposed a certain toxicity in the OSS community that I really wish wasn&amp;rsquo;t so prevalent.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting on and off on dev.to but I never introduced myself so let me preface this post with a bit about me to give some context.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using open source and Linux on and off since the early 2000s. My first Linux distribution was Caldera 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker IPV6 Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/docker-ipv6-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/docker-ipv6-guide/</guid>
      <description>IPV4 IPV6  Step 1, enable in the Daemon Step 2, Firewall rules Step 3, Docker Compose + IPV6 Step 4, Resolve NAT Issues   Final thoughts. Unconfirmed Fix  I spent a good bit of time trying to figure this out, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d record this for posterity&amp;rsquo;s sake and others might benefit.
Assumptions:
 You are somewhat familiar with docker You have some exposure with docker-compose You have at least a basic understanding of networking fundamentals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Docker Deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/poor-mans-docker-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/26/poor-mans-docker-deployment/</guid>
      <description>SSL NGINX  NGINX vhost config.   Docker application  Docker Systemd script   Docker Check List. Final stage  I have had several use cases where I want to deploy things in docker for multiple reasons, but ease of deployment is a big one. Low entry bar, less maintenance that makes docker deployment more appealing. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the resources to do a full K8 deployment and ended up with this pattern I wanted to share with others</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Raid 1 to Raid 5 on Linux file systems</title>
      <link>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/22/converting-raid-1-to-raid-5-on-linux-file-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.esamir.com/20/8/22/converting-raid-1-to-raid-5-on-linux-file-systems/</guid>
      <description>Converting from Raid 1 to Raid 5 This assumes you have a functional Raid 1 and wish to convert it to a Raid 5.
Disclaimer: At some point during this process I realized that I had a bad mother board. The reason my /dev/sdd1 failed wasn&amp;rsquo;t the drive, but the bus on the board. That being said, this is the unverified procedure.
I&amp;rsquo;m running on Ubuntu 12.10 but you should be able to do this on any modern Linux distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>